What went on the screen was nothing compared to what went on behind the scenes.
RKO 281 is a drama, history, tv movie film directed by Benjamin Ross.
In 1939, boy-wonder Orson Welles leaves New York, where he has succeeded in radio and theater, and,
hired by RKO Pictures, moves to Hollywood with the purpose of making his first film.
Orson Welles, played by Liev Schreiber.
William Randolph Hearst, played by James Cromwell.
Marion Davies, played by Melanie Griffith.
Herman Mankiewicz, played by John Malkovich.
Gregg Toland, played by Liam Cunningham.
Louis B. Mayer, played by David Suchet.
RKO 281 is a 1999 American historical drama television film directed by Benjamin Ross, written by John Logan, and
starring Liev Schreiber, James Cromwell, Melanie Griffith, John Malkovich, Roy Scheider, and Liam Cunningham.
The film depicts the troubled production behind the 1941 film Citizen Kane.
The film's title is a reference to the original
production number of Citizen Kane.
It premiered on HBO on November 20, 1999.
The film explores themes of cinema on cinema, yellow press,
movie business, biography, antisemitism.
The tone is emotional.